-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 旺仔仔 发条橙 Gabriella 凤梨酥
校对: 柚子茶 月光取暖
Peek-a-boo!
玩躲猫猫啦!
No, no, no, no, no.
不玩了 不玩了
I didn't mean to startle you, my little baby.
不是故意吓到你的 小宝贝
Shh, shh, shh.
嘘 不哭了
# Hush, little vampire, don't say a word #
# 吸血鬼宝贝不说话 #
# Papa's gonna bite the head off a bird #
# 爸爸为你咬下鸟脑袋 #
A-bitty goo-bah!
你这个调皮鬼!
I vant to kiss your tush.
来让我亲一个
I vant to kiss your tush!
让我亲下你的小虎牙!
Nice, but maybe a little more square footage.
不错 要是面积再大一点就更好了
I want a lot of monsters here.
我想要有很多的怪物住在这里
I'm gonna get you, little Mavis.
我来抓你啦 梅维丝
I'm gonna get you! Oy.
要抓到你啦! 哎哟
What out there?
那外面是什么?
Oh, we never go out there.
哦 我们从不到外面去的
Ever.
永远都不
"And then the monsters ran away and were forced into hiding."
"然后怪物们都四处逃窜 不得不躲避起来"
"But Harry the Human found them and jumped out from under their bed."
"但人类哈利还是找到了他们 并从他们的床底下跳出来"
- I'm scared!  - "And burned their clothes
- 我好害怕!  - "烧掉了怪物的衣服
and bit their toes!"
啃掉了他们的脚趾头!"
"And took their candy!"
"还把他们的糖果拿走了!"
Don't take my candy.
不准抢我的糖果
Babyclaws, you don't need to be frightened.
小宝贝 你不用这么害怕
I promised your mommy I would protect you forever.
我答应你妈妈会永远保护你的
# My beautiful May-vay #
# 我可爱的小梅梅 #
# Let me wipe all your poop away #
# 爸爸辛苦把你拉扯大 #
# Those humans are nas-tay #
# 那些人类都很可恶 #
# So with Daddy you will stay #
# 爸爸会永远保护你 #
# And if a human tries to harm you #
# 如果有人类想伤害你 #
# I'll simply say... #
# 我只会这样说... #
# Because you're Daddy's girl #
# 因为你是爸爸的小宝贝 #
# Daddy's girl #
# 爸爸的小宝贝 #
# I'm your Vlad-y daddy... #
# 我是爱你的爸爸... #
Just bend the legs and push off.
只要屈膝然后向前一跃
Trust me, mouse.
相信我 小老鼠
- Ha-ha!  - I can fly! I can fly!
- 哈哈!  - 我会飞了! 我会飞了!
Look at you!
快看!
Faster, baby! Faster!
用力飞 宝贝! 再用力飞!
- Whoo-hoo!  - You got it, my little voodoo doll!
- 喔!  - 你做到了 我的小巫师娃娃!
Excuse me, sir.
不好意思 先生
What? What?
怎么了? 什么事?
Ow. I'm okay.
嗷 我没事
It's ready.
都准备好了
Looks good.
看起来不错
Only monsters can get in?
只有怪物能进来吗?
Oh, absolutely.
哦 绝对没错
It's hidden real nicely.
已经完美的隐藏好了
You got 400 acres of haunted forest in front of you.
在它前面有400英亩的亡魂森林
You got the Land of the Undead on the perimeters.
周围全都是活死人墓地
Any humans daring to even look over there will run away real quick.
任何走近此地的人类都会吓得逃之夭夭
But, of course, be smart.
当然 放聪明点的话
No bonfires, no firework shows.
不能有篝火 不能有烟火表演
Yeah, yeah, no, no. No fire, I get it, I get it.
好吧 我知道了 不能有火光 我明白了
It's time, my darling Martha.
终于等到这一天了 亲爱的玛莎
The place we always talked about for Mavis.
这里就是我们一直想为梅维丝建造的地方
No one will ever harm her here.
在这里永远不会有人伤害到她
精灵旅馆
N年后
Yeah, it's a mess back there.
后车厢的行李就麻烦你了
Welcome to Hotel Transylvania!
欢迎来到精灵旅社!
Human-free since 1898.
1898年至今无人类出现
Your safest destination.
这里是你最安全的港湾
Take an itinerary.
拿好你的旅行指南
I have personally designed a spectacular schedule of events,
里面有我亲自为我女儿明天的生日宴会
all leading to my daughter's birthday extravaganza tomorrow.
设计的豪华活动安排
We always look forward to coming every year, Count.
我们每年都盼望着来这里 伯爵
We enjoy the safety so much.
我们非常享受这里的安全
Of course. That's why we built it.
那当然了 这里就是为此而建的
Yes, good evening.
晚上好啊
Thank you, Marty.
谢谢光临 玛蒂
You look pale, as well.
你看起来还是那样苍白无力
Sir, sir, sir!
长官 有事禀报!
We have an urgent plumbing issue.
我们发现一个紧急的管道问题
Plumbing? On it.
管道? 知道了
Mr. Ghouligan!
乌拉干先生!
There is a clogged toilet in room 348.
348号房间的厕所发生堵塞
It's okay. We all get stomach aches, Mr. Bigfoot.
没事的 每个人都会肚子疼 大脚先生
Hey, kids, reel it in.
嘿 孩子们 别到处乱跑
You're only supposed to make Mom and Dad miserable.
你们这是要爸爸妈妈难堪
Now, now, is that any way to behave?
好了 能不能乖一点啊?
This is a hotel, not a cemetery.
这里可是旅馆 不是墓地哦
Sorry, Uncle Drac.
抱歉 德库拉叔叔
Drac! How are ya?
德库拉! 你还好吗?
Wayne, my old friend!
韦恩 我的老朋友!
Couldn't wait for this weekend.
我们已经等不及这个周末了
Always great to be out ofthe shadows for a couple days.
好些日子想死了要出来透透气了
The family looks beautiful.
这一家子看起来真漂亮
Let me just clean up their filth.
让我来好好给他们清理一下
Housekeeping!
客房服务!
Frankie, my boy! Look at you!
弗兰基 伙计! 看看你自己!
Still traveling by mail, Mr. Cheapo, huh?
还是和以前一样打包出行 吝啬先生 哈?
It's not a money thing.
这根本不是钱的问题
I have a plane phobia, okay?
我有飞机恐惧症 你知道吗?
I mean, at any moment, those engines could catch...
我的意思是 那些飞机引擎随时都可能...
Fire! Yeah, yeah.
着火! 没说错吧
"Fire bad."
着火可不好
We know.
怪物都知道
Augustus, Porridge Head, come on!
奥古斯塔斯 粥点部长 给我放下!
Does that look like Frankenstein's head?
那个看起来像是科学怪人的头吗?
Hey, Drac, buddy, what's going on with your cape there?
嘿 德库拉 兄弟 你的披肩是怎么回事?
What do you mean? Oh!
什么意思? 哦!
Who pinched me?
谁在捏我?
Guilty. You're irresistible.
抱歉 你太迷人了
Yes, very amusing, Invisible Man.
是啊 你嘴巴太甜了 隐形人
Hello. Great to "see" you.
你好 "见"到你很高兴
Never gets old.
还跟从前一样
Ho-ho-ho.
哈哈
Missed me.
没打到哦
Missed me, missed me, missed me.
打不到 打不到 打不到哦
Okay, you win. Hold this bacon.
好吧 你赢了 拿着这条培根
Why am I holding bacon... Ahh!
我为什么要拿着培根... 啊!
No! Get 'em off!
不! 快下来!
Here comes the party!
派对达人来啦!
Hello, Murray!
你好啊 默里!
Drac, what's up, buddy?
德库拉 你还好吗?
The sand, Murray, the sand!
沙子 默里 到处都是沙子!
Always with the sand.
又是风尘仆仆而来
Whee!
哟!
Wolfie! Wanda! Frank!
小狼! 旺达! 还有弗兰克!
I love this guy.
我爱死你了
He always bringing it full tilt.
总是和我配合完美
You're looking skinny, too.
你看起来还是那么瘦
Now that you're just a head.
现在只剩一个头了
Okay, you'll pay for that.
好吧 我会找你算账的
So what's up, Drac?
到底怎么回事 德库拉?
The hotel is looking off the hook.
看样子旅馆正在重整旗鼓
Hey, guys, watch this.
嘿 伙计们 看看这个
By the way, you were right about those directions.
顺便说一下 你的这些发展方向都是可行的
Oh, good, good.
哦 很好 不错
Yeah, I took the Tigris
我让底格里斯河(流经土耳其和伊拉克)与尼罗河通流
through the Nile, and there was absolutely no traffic.
这样就绝对无路可走了
You're kidding me.
你这是在和我开玩笑
Right in my lobby?
竟然在我的大厅放屁?
Drac, I swear, man, I don't run like that.
德库拉 我发誓不是我 那不是我的放屁风格
Housekeeping!
客房服务!
I was not the cause of that.
那屁不是我放的
We're ready!
都准备好啦!
If only Martha were here to see this.
要是玛莎能看见就好了
She's always here, Wanda.
她从未离开过 旺达
Okay, friends,
好了 朋友们
I am so glad you are here to celebrate.
很高兴各位能亲临派对现场
Another birthday for my sweet little Mavis,
我的宝贝女儿梅维丝一年一度的生日盛会
and another successful year of refuge from them!
同时又是成功躲避人类的新一年!
These are recent human images
这些都是我们监控器拍摄到的
our surveillance has uncovered.
最新的人类图片
They are getting fatter so as to overpower us.
他们变得越来越胖 为的是能更加压制我们
And they are wearing less clothing,
他们穿的衣服也越来越少
allowing more movement to strangle us
他们就更方便勒死我们
or cut open our heads and put candy in them.
把我们的头砍下来装糖果
But they will never
但是现在他们永远都不会
find us here.
在这里找到我们了
Evil villain, you will never win!
邪恶的坏人 你们不会得逞的!
Okie doke. The fun starts in 30 minutes.
乡亲们 30分钟后开始狂欢
Right now, I have to see my little girl.
现在我要去看下我的宝贝女儿了
She's not so little anymore!
她不再是小姑娘啦!
Yes, she is!
不 她就是!
What's going on out there?
发生什么事了?
Are we at the hotel?
我们已经到旅馆了吗?
Frank, did you book us for a tandem massage?
弗兰克 你给我们预定了双人按摩吗?
Did you get us a table at Hunchback's?
你为我们准备好了一张驼背桌子吗?
Did you do anything?
该做的都做到了吗?
You're welcome.
不用客气
What's going on?
搞什么情况?
Dad, you said that
老爹 你说过的
when I turned 118 I could go out into the world
当我118岁的时候 我就能像其他大人一样
like every other adult that gets to come and go from this hotel.
自由出入这间旅馆 到外面的世界看看
"But, Mavey Wavey, it's not safe. Bleh, bleh-bleh."
"但是 梅梅 外面不安全 叽叽哇哇 叽哇叽哇"
Dad, 30 years ago, you promised.
老爹 30年前你答应过我的
I remember, we were both eating mice,
我一直记得 当时我们在吃老鼠
and you specifically said that you gave me your word.
你很明确的说你会兑现你的诺言的
Do not disturb.
请勿打扰
- Do not disturb.  - Do not disturb.
- 请勿打扰  - 请勿打扰
Do not disturb.
请勿打扰
- Do not disturb.  - Do not disturb.
- 请勿打扰  - 请勿打扰
- Do not disturb.  - Good morning, Your Eminence.
- 请勿打扰  - 早上好 阁下大人
Maid, clean up this room!
女佣 这间房需要打扫!
It's you. Glad you could make it.
你来啦 很高兴你能来
- Is she up yet?  - Oh, she's up.
- 她起来了吗?  - 哦 起来了
She's ready to go. And by "go," I mean go. As in, go check the world out.
她已经准备好出去了 出去看外面的世界
What you gonna do? What you gonna say?
你准备怎么做? 你准备怎么说?
I got it covered. Please, relax. Just do your job.
我已经安排好了 别紧张 做好本分的事
Good morning, Mavey Wavey!
早上好 梅梅!
Happy birthday, my little mouse!
生日快乐 我的小老鼠!
Thank you, Dad.
谢谢你 老爹
I know it's my birthday.
我知道今天是我的生日
I have so much fun planned. Whoo-hoo!
我为你安排了一大堆的娱乐活动 喔呵!
But first, we go catch some scorpions together,
但是 我们先一起去抓些蝎子
just the two of us, yes, dead-ums?
就咱俩哦 怎么样?
Dad, please, let me speak.
老爹 等一下 让我说两句
There's something we have to talk about.
有些事情我想和你谈谈
You want to go out into the world. You can.
你想去外面的世界 你可以去了
Aha!
啊!
I knew you were gonna say that.
我就知道你会这样说
But, Dad, you gave me your word,
但是 老爹 你答应过我
and you know that I know that a Dracula's word is sacred.
而且你很清楚吸血鬼的话是神圣的
That our trust is the core of our...
信任就是我们的...
Wait, what?
等下 你刚说什么?
I said you can go.
我说你可以去了
You're just playing with me.
你这是在耍我
No, no, no, no. You're old enough to drive a hearse now,
不是的 你已经到了能驾驶一辆灵车的年龄了
you're old enough to make your own choices.
你已经有能力做你自己的选择了
You can go.
你可以去了
Holy rabies! Holy rabies!
太棒了! 太棒啦!
Whoa, whoa. Stop.
哇 等一下
Wait a second, sweet fangs.
稍微等一下 亲爱的小尖牙
Where are you going?
你要去哪里?
Oh, well, I'm going to paradise,
哦 这个 我要去天堂
and this is just some stuff that I thought I would need.
我觉得这些东西应该用得上
- Paradise?  - Yeah, you know.
- 天堂?  - 是的 你懂的
It's that place out there where you and Mom met.
就是你和妈妈相遇的地方
Auntie Wanda says you two
旺达姨妈说
were just like, Zing!
当时你俩一见钟情!
I don't know from "Zing."
我不知道什么"一见钟情"
Where did you find that card?
你在哪儿找到那张卡片的?
In one of your drawers.
在你的抽屉里
Why won't you ever tell me about how you met?
你为什么从不告诉我你们是怎么相遇的呢?
It's actually Hawaii.
其实那里是夏威夷
Ha-what-what?
夏什么夷?
Look, honey, I know you're excited,
听着 亲爱的 我知道你很激动
but everyone has gone to great lengths to come see you on your birthday.
但是现在所有人都是大老远跑来为你庆祝生日的
I know. They always do.
我知道 他们每次都是
But aren't I getting a little old for these parties?
但我是不是已经不太适合参与这些活动了?
I love them, but I really want to see new things.
我爱他们 但是我真的很想接触些新的事物
Maybe meet somebody my age.
或者认识一些年龄相仿的人
Come on. No, no, don't do that.
好吧 不 别这样
Don't give me the pouty bat face.
不要可怜巴巴的样子
Okay, there is a human village
好吧 离墓地不远的地方
just a little ways past the cemetery.
有一个人类的村子
You could go there and be back in, like, 30 minutes or so.
你可以去那里看看 然后差不多30分钟后就回来
It should be plenty for your first time.
对于第一次出行30分钟已经足够了
Well, it's not Ha-wee-wee, but I guess
好吧 虽然不是去什么夏威威
it's still technically out there.
但总算是能出去一回
Okay, okay, okay!
好了 好了 我知道了!
Thanks for trusting me.
非常感谢您这么相信我
Of course, my little one.
当然了 我的小乖乖
I gave you my word.
我兑现了我的承诺
Hey, honey!
嘿 亲爱的!
- Look at this!  - Hey, guys.
- 看这里!  - 嘿 各位
You excited about tomorrow?
你这是为明天的生日而兴奋吗?
Not as excited as I am right now.
我现在有更兴奋的事
You're not gonna believe this, but Dad is letting me
你们不会相信的 但是老爹终于允许我
go out on my own to see a human village!
独自去外面看看人类的村子了!
- What?  - No!
- 什么?  - 不会吧!
Excuse me. Drac!
请让一下 德库拉!
Have you lost it?
你疯了吗?
Letting your own daughter out there
你常对我们说外面的人类很恐怖
with those horrible humans you always tell us about?
但现在你却让你自己的女儿去冒险?
That's why you built this place.
你忘了建造旅馆的原因了吗
They hate us. They're vicious.
人类讨厌我们 人类都是邪恶的
And they're very loud!
而且他们说话很吵闹!
Auntie Eunice, maybe they've changed.
尤妮斯姨妈 也许那些人类现在变了
I'm just gonna fly down the street and see how it goes.
我只是想飞到街上看看真实的现状
Okay, honey, be safe.
好吧 亲爱的 注意安全
Bring warm clothes and a sword.
多穿点别着凉 要带上魔剑
And look out for pitchforks.
要小心干草叉子
Don't you let anyone scoop your brains out, either.
同样要小心不能让任何人把你的脑子铲出来
Maybe stay in the shadows.
也许待在阴暗处比较好
It's more fun to just observe from under a house.
在屋檐下静静的观察会更有趣的
Guys, guys. She can handle it.
好了 伙计们 她能处理好一切的
She's a Dracula, for Pete's sake.
看在上帝的份上 她可是一个吸血鬼
But seriously, watch out for fire.
但值得注意的是 小心火烛
Fire bad.
玩火者自焚
Bye, everyone.
再见了 各位
Whoo-hoo!
喔啊!
Drac, I can't believe how calm you are about her leaving.
德库拉 我不敢相信你能如此冷静地看着她离开
I'm proud of you.
真为你骄傲
Drac? Drac?
德库拉? 你在哪儿?
Where did Drac go?
德库拉去哪儿了?
Whoo-hoo!
喔啊!
This is awesome!
太了不起了!
There's the cemetery, just like Dad said.
这里有一个墓地 和老爹说的一样
Whoo-hoo!
喔啊!
Uh... Hello?
呃... 有人吗?
Anybody out there?
有人在吗?
- Vampire.  - Bite toes!
- 吸血鬼  - 啃脚趾!
Oh!
哦!
Hi, humans.
嗨 各位
Everything okay? My name is Mavis Dracula, and I...
大家都好吗? 我叫梅维丝·德库拉 我是...
Vampire.
吸血鬼
- Burn clothes.  - Burn my clothes?
- 烧掉衣服  - 要烧掉我的衣服?
- Really? Um...  - Vampire!
- 真的吗? 呃...  - 吸血鬼!
- We take your candy.  - Candy!
- 我们来拿你的糖果  - 糖果!
I'm friendly. I really am.
我很友好的 真的
- Calm down, now.  - Candy.
- 冷静点  - 糖果
I just wanted to say hi.
我只是想跟大家打声招呼
Please. I've never hurt anyone.
别这样 我从未伤害过任何人
I'm homeschooled.
我是一个宅女
Is that garlic?
那是蒜油味的吗?
Holy rabies, you're on fire.
我的乖乖 你们着火了
Can I do anything? Can I help you?
有什么需要帮忙的吗? 要我帮你们吗?
Dad was right.
老爹说的没错
It worked.
成功了
Now my baby will be safe forever.
现在我的宝贝女儿永远都安全了
All right, everybody, get back to work now.
好了 各位 都回去工作了
Hey. You don't need a mannequin.
嘿 你不能把模特带走
Leave the mannequin here. Come on.
把模特放下 快点
Where you been?
你去哪儿了?
Why you sneaking around?
为啥鬼鬼祟祟的到处跑?
Shh. Quiet.
嘘 闭嘴
Sweetheart, have you returned so soon?
宝贝 你这么快就回来了?
Oh. Come in, Dad.
哦 进来吧 老爹
How'd it go? How was the big world?
感觉如何? 外面的世界怎么样?
How was it out there?
有没有什么新发现?
It was okay, Dad.
还好啦 老爹
What? What's the matter?
怎么了? 说说又何妨呢?
Dad, you were right.
老爹 你说的没错
Humans are awful.
那些人类很可怕
They were everything you said.
和你说的完全一样
- They wanted to bite my toes.  - Your toes?
- 他们要啃我的脚趾  - 你的脚趾?
And they had garlic on bread.
他们还把大蒜汁浇在面包上
What? Look at me.
什么? 看看我吧
I'm getting goose bumps, I'm so scared.
我浑身都起鸡皮疙瘩了 吓死我了
I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
很抱歉 宝贝
I hate that you had to see that.
我难过让你看到事实
I'm so sorry I doubted you.
很抱歉我不相信你的话
I'll never leave here again.
我再也不离开这里了
Okay. Okay.
好了 没事了
Look, Daddy's going to make you the bestest birthday ever.
听着 老爹我将要为你举办一场最好的生日宴会
Look what I brought you.
看看我给你带什么来了
Your worm cakes.
你最爱的虫虫蛋糕
Don't be sad anymore.
不要再难过了
Remember, this is the year we open Mommy's present for you.
还记得吧 今年我们将要打开妈妈给你留着的礼物
What did she get me?
她给我准备什么了?
We'll see.
拭目以待哦
She said never to open until you're 118.
她说了只有你到了118岁的时候才能打开
We've waited this long.
我们为此等了很久很久哦
You eat your worm cakes.
先吃着你的虫虫蛋糕吧
You come down whenever you're ready, honey.
等你准备好了就下来 亲爱的
- Phew.  - Ooh.
- 啊  - 哦
What did you do?
你做了什么啊?
What I had to.
不得不做的事
Mm-hmm.
嗯嗯
She'll thank me one day.
她总有一天会感激我的
Yeah, that's what the guy who shrunk my head said.
是的 这是把我头绑起来的那个人说的
Ahh.
啊
Yes, what do you want, a cookie?
你想要什么 饼干吗?
You did all right, man.
你做的很好 老兄
Move on already.
继续向前走
Phew!
啊!
Yeah.
太好了
Vampire! Vampire!
吸血鬼! 吸血鬼!
A human.
一个人类
Who are you? And how did you find this place?
你是谁? 你是怎么找到这个地方的?
Oh, I'm Jonathan.
哦 我叫乔纳森
And I was just mountain climbing with some dudes...
我只是和一群兄弟在爬山...
and heard this story about a spooky forest.
然后听到一个关于幽魂森林的传说
And who's not going to go into a spooky forest, right?
任何人都想进入一个幽魂森林的 不是吗?
So, then I see these goofy-looking dudes on fire.
后来 我看到了那些着火的傻头傻脑的家伙
And I just kind of followed them to this, like, amazing castle.
然后我就一路跟着他们来到了这里 一座不可思议的城堡
But, of course, be smart.
当然了 放聪明点的话
No bonfires, no firework shows.
不能有篝火 不能有烟火表演
- How many of you are there?  - Just me.
- 你们来了多少人?  - 就我一个
I like to hit it alone.
我就是个独行侠
You meet so many awesome people in the youth hostels.
在青年旅舍可以碰到好多牛人
Hey, speaking of awesome, that cape thing is killing it.
说道牛气 这件斗篷简直酷爆了
Is there, like, a costume party here?
这里是在开化妆舞会吗?
What have I done?
我做了什么?
This is all my fault.
这都是我的错
You have to leave.
你得走
- Oh, no.  - Excuse me.
- 哦 糟糕  - 打扰您一下
One of your piranhas in the lake is very rude.
在你河里有条食人鲳太放肆了
He ate my sister-in-law.
把我的小姨子给吞了
Be right with you.
您稍等下
Mr. Dracula, we asked for a room with a view of the pool.
德库拉先生 我们要看得到游泳池的房间
The room's fine. We want to book a massage.
房间不错 我们想预约个按摩
- Yes, Swedish.  - Shiatsu.
- 对 要瑞士式按摩  - 日式的
- Aromatherapy.  - Lower back.
- 要涂香料  - 还要照顾到下背
- Do you have hot-stone?  - We want a massage.
- 你们有热石按摩吗?  - 我们来次按摩
- I'll get back to you, Mr. Hydraberg.  - I hope so.
- 我去去就回 六头怪先生  - 但愿
- I doubt it.  - See that you do.
- 强烈怀疑  - 说话算话哦
- That's Ms. Hydraberg.  - Thanks.
- 是六头怪女士啦  - 谢谢了
- Yes, nice to see you.  - Dude, seriously, what's up?
- 很高兴见到你  - 老哥 说真的 到底怎么了?
It's kind of funky to breathe under here.
这下面有股怪味
Drac. Hey, Drac. How'd it go with Mavey?
德库拉 嘿 梅维丝怎么样了?
Hey. Where'd you go?
你要去哪?
Wow!
哇!
This room's kind of small for a big castle.
这城堡这么大 房间却有点小
No bed, but check out these awesome dustpans they give you.
没床 不过这里摆着的簸箕真是酷啊
Quiet, you fool.
安静 傻帽
What weapons are you keeping in this container?
你在这个包里藏了什么凶器?
Your pitchforks?
干草叉子?
Oh!
哦!
I can't breathe.
我喘不上气了
It's killing me.
我要死了
Yeah, definitely due for a fluff and fold.
对啊 臭袜子能杀人啊
What is this?
这又是啥?
A torture device?
刑具?
A secret mind controller?
精神控制仪?
You won't read my thoughts.
休想窥看我的想法
l won't let you.
我不会让你得逞
Dude, it's just music.
老哥 这就是用来听音乐的
Here, try it.
来试试看嘛
Ohh!
哦!
It's taking my soul!
它摄走了我的灵魂
What? It's a good jam. Don't be a grandpa.
啥? 这歌的节奏不错 开放点嘛
You need to go.
你得给我走
No human has ever entered this castle. And if someone should see you,
没有人类踏入过这座城堡 如果谁看到了你
the safety of the hotel, the sanctuary, no one would ever come again.
城堡就危险了 没人会再到这来 没人会再把它当成避难所
Yeah, go for it.
好耶 在说一次
"Ever come again!"
"没人会再来！"
l love your Dracula voice. It's so over the top.
我超爱你的德库拉腔 简直碉堡了
And Mavis, if she saw you, she would know that I lied. No!
还有梅维丝 如果她看到了你 她就会发现我骗了她 不要啊!
Who's Mavis? Is this her room?
梅维丝是谁? 这是她的房间吗?
I'm good with a roommate.
多一个室友也没什么
l had six brothers growing up, so I could totally share.
我家里有六个兄弟 分享对我来说完全没问题
I can't kill him.
我不能宰了他
It would set monsters back hundreds of years.
这会让怪物的操行倒退好几年
One time, in Hamburg, I roomed with this dude
有次 我在汉堡和个老兄睡一间屋子
who I caught stealing my shampoo.
结果我发现他偷我的洗发水
I said, "Whoa, man," and he threw a flower pot at me, but he was cool.
我叫了声"哇 没搞错吧" 然后他就朝我丢花瓶 不过他挺酷的
What are you babbling about?
你唧唧歪歪的说什么?
What? Whoa.
啥? 哇
Check out these awesome costumes.
看看这些酷炫的道具服
Costumes.
道具服
What's this? Sorry, man. I just can't be without my backpack.
做什么呢? 对不起老兄 我没了背包可不行
- You know, everything I own's in there.  - It'll be right here.
- 你知道的 我的家当都在里面呢  - 我们就把它放在这
Okay, I just... I love my backpack.
好啦 只是... 我爱自己的包
Whoa. Hey, what are you doing?
哇 嘿 你干什么?
What are you... What are you doing to my hair?
手往哪放呢... 你对我的头发做了什么?
Stop. Oh, wait, that tickles.
快住手 等下 好痒
Come on, man.
别玩了 老兄
Check it out. I'm a Franken-homie.
看我 我是个居家版的科学怪人
- Yes, hello.  - Look at me!
- 对 好啊  - 看我这里!
This is totally normal, not a problem here. This is just a monster with me.
这完全正常 什么事情没有 我只不过带了个怪物
Man, everybody stepped it up tonight.
老兄 今天大家都盛装打扮啊
Wait, why are we going to the front door? Are we leaving?
等下 为什么往大门走? 我们要走了吗?
Bonjour, Dracula!
你好啊 德库拉
Hey, Sniffy. What's going on?
嘿 长鼻子 什么事啊?
Not right now, Quasimodo.
现在没空 卡西莫多
What?
什么?
No. Don't be absurd.
说什么傻话呢
It's not a human, but Mr.Dracula
这不是人类 是德库拉先生
How ridiculous. It's me.
真是荒谬 是我啊
Monsieur.
先生
- The devilled lizard fingers.  - Devilled lizard fingers?
- 这是芥末蜥蜴指  - 芥末蜥蜴指?
I asked for spleens-in-blankets.
我要的是脾脏卷啊
You ugly fool! I told you, he doesn't like
大白痴! 我告诉过你 他不喜欢
- the lizard fingers!  - But you said...
- 蜥蜴指头!  - 但是你说...
Whoa. Check that costume out.
哇 看看那套打扮
Wow. Seriously, I just have to ask you: How are you pulling this off?
我得问问你 怎么才能出这种效果?
I mean, it looks so real.
我说 看起来好真啊
Like, I could just put my hand right through...
就像是 可以把手伸进去...
What do you think you're doing?
你在干什么呢?
She's real. You're real!
她是真的 你也是真的!
Yeah, and I'll give you a real beating. Keep your hands out of my wife!
没错 我的拳头也是真真的 离我老婆远点
Oh, no.
哦 惨了
Honey, I just didn't know where you were.
宝贝 我刚才不知道你去哪了
We thought you were still out.
我们以为你还在外面
Oh, no. I don't know why I eve rwanted to leave.
哦 我不知道自己为什么会想出门
The humans are so boring.
人类好无聊
Mavis, honey, are you all right?
梅维丝宝贝 你没事吧?
Yeah, I think so. That was weird.
我想没事 那感觉真怪
My head hurts.
头好疼啊
- Um, who is that?  - Who is what?
- 嗯 那个人是谁?  - 什么谁?
Oh, that.
哦 那个啊
That is nobody.
哪有什么人
- Seriously, Dad?  - "Dad"?
- 还没玩够呢 老爸?  - "老爸"
Yeah, I know, Dracula's daughter. Everyone freaks out at first.
对 我知道德库拉的闺女 大家第一次听说都会吓到
Dracula?
还德库拉?
Okay, we got to go.
好吧 我们得走了
Please don't kill me. I'm so young.
不要杀我 我还年少
I have so many places I want to see.
还有很多地方想见识
I've got tickets to six Dave Matthews Band concerts.
我还要去戴夫·马休斯乐队的演唱会
I'm getting out of here.
我要从这里出去
Shut up already.
给我闭嘴
It's impossible for me to think with all your noise.
你吵成这样 我想不了问题
Sorry, Glen. Go back to sleep.
对不起 格林 回去睡吧
- Wait. Aren't you going to suck my blood?  - Classic human paranoia.
- 等等 你不吸我的血吗?  - 典型的人类偏见
Human blood is so fatty, and you never know where it's been.
人血脂肪太多 而且你还不知道那人都干过什么
So, Dracula doesn't drink blood?
所以德库拉不吸血?
No, I use a blood substitute.
我用其他东西代替血
Either Near Blood or Blood Beaters. You can't tell the difference.
血浆啊还有和血差不多的东西 都喝不出什么不同
So, wow, you're, like, the real Count Dracula.
所以 你就是 货真价实的德库拉
Like, "I'm Dracula. Bleh, bleh-bleh."
像是"我是德库拉 吧啦吧吧啦"
I've never said that in my life. "Bleh, bleh-bleh."
我活到现在还没说过一次"吧啦吧吧啦"
I don't know where that comes from.
都不知道这说法哪里来的
Can I just ask, what exactly is this place?
我能问问这到底是哪吗?
What is this place?
这里是哪?
It's a place I built for all those monsters out there,
这是我为了所有怪物建造的地方
lurking in the shadows, hiding from the persecution of humankind.
他们在黑暗中游荡 躲避人类的迫害
A place for them and their families to come to and be themselves.
在这里 他们能和自己的家人一起回归自我
A place void of torches, pitchforks, angry mobs.
这里没有火把 干草叉子 和愤怒的人群
A place of peace, relaxation
只有平合和舒适
and tranquility.
还有宁静
Cool. So, it's like a hotel for monsters?
酷啊 所以这就是给怪物开的旅馆?
Yes, exactly. "A hotel for monsters." Way to sum it up.
对 没错 "给怪物开的旅馆" 总结的好
Okay, hop on my back. We're leaving.
好了 跳到我背上来 得走了
Oh, man, you're a bat now.
哦 老兄 你变成蝙蝠了
l always wanted to fly. What's it like?
我真的很想飞呢 感觉怎么样?
This is insane. Wait. Wait, I want to stay.
这太疯狂了 等等 我不要走
Can Frankenstein sign my costume? Can I meet the lnvisible Man?
能让科学怪人给我的衣服签名吗? 能让我见见隐形人吗?
Hey, if I stuck my hand in the lnvisible Man's mouth,
嘿 如果我把手伸到隐形人嘴里
- would it disappear?  - Hi.
- 会怎么样?  - 嗨
Mavey! What are you doing, my sweet little blood orange?
梅梅! 你干什么来了 我的小血橙?
Our friend was just leaving.
我们的朋友正要走呢
Yeah, he was flying me out the window.
对 他拉着我从窗户飞出来
This guy, he's so funny.
这家伙 他真是搞笑
Look, you have something on your face.
看那 你脸上沾了点东西
Play along if you ever want to see your precious backpack.
想要再见到你的宝贝背包就好好配合
Whoa. So, wait, you didn't have any clothes on when you were a bat?
哇 等等 你在蝙蝠形态时没有衣服?
Or were they bat-sized?
还是 它们就是蝙蝠形的?
Who exactly is that?
这到底是谁?
Hmm. Honeybat.
嗯 我的小蝙蝠
You see, it's your birthday.
你看 今天是你生日
And you know I want you to have the bestest, specialest party of your life.
你知道 我想给你办场 人生最精彩最好的派对
So, well, I needed some help.
嗯 所以我需要个帮手
You needed help?
你需要帮手?
Well, look, I am very good, but I thought it would be
听着 我可能干了 但是我想
even more bestest, specialest if someone closer to your age helped plan the party.
如果找个跟你差不多的人来帮我安排 那就会更特别 更好的
- You're my age?  - Sure.
- 你跟我差不多大?  - 当然了
Well, how old are you?
你多大?
118.
118岁
One hundred and...
一百...
Yeah, I'm 121.
对 我121了
- Really?  - Mm-hmm.
- 真的?  - 对啊
You see? Everything is very, very normal.
看到没? 一切正常 超正常
I'm throwing a party, and he's helping.
我办派对 他来帮忙
- Sir, there's an emergency.  - Not now.
- 先生 有紧急情况  - 现在没空
Can't you see we're in the middle of something very normal here?
看不出来我们现在正在做一件超级正常的事吗?
Wait, what's going on here?
等等 出了什么事了?
There's an emergency in your precious hotel, and you're not running to fix it?
你的宝贝饭店里面有紧急情况 你却不去处理?
Why? Is it because of him?
为什么不去? 因为他?
Whoa, look at my face.
哇 看着我
No, precious bones, it's not because of him.
不是 心肝宝贝 不是因为他
Good. Then go check on the emergency, and I'll keep him company.
好啊 去看看有什么紧急情况 我来陪他
- No! Anything but that!  - What?
- 不行! 这事绝对不行!  - 什么?
I mean, because he needs time to plan.
我是说 他得做计划呢
And if you're keeping him company, then he's not planning.
如果你陪着他 他就计划不了了
He is company-keeping,
如果有人陪着他
and then the plan, it's... It doesn't get planned.
然后 计划 这... 计划就没人去计划了
- Mm-hmm. Good one.  - Shut up!
- 嗯 编的好  - 闭嘴!
Okay. So, maybe if you're not planning later, we can hang out.
好吧 等你之后不做计划了 我们就能一起打混了
- Sounds good.  - Yes. You hear that?
- 听着挺好  - 对你听到了吗?
It sounds good.
听起来不错
So you will hang out. See you later, my honey. Lovely.
你们等下再一起玩 再见了 小心肝 小宝贝
Okay, you're not hanging out.
好了 你们不能一起
Because you are leaving.
因为你要走了
But the opposite, you said.
但是 你不是说
But, sir, the emergency.
先生 还有紧急情况呢
Follow me.
跟上来
Boy, that kid smelt.
娘诶 这小子好臭
Where are we going?
我们这是去哪?
Just getting rid of you
从密道把你送走
through a secret tunnel so she does not see us.
这样她就看不见我们了
So, can I ask you a question?
我可以问你个问题吗?
Is that real, about the garlic thing?
所以 你们怕洋葱是真的吗?
Yes, I cannot have it. My throat swells.
对 我不能吃 喉咙会肿
Huh. Wooden stake to the heart?
嗯 用木桩穿心你会死吗?
Yeah, well, who wouldn't that kill?
木桩穿心谁死不了啊?
Ah. Here we go.
好了 就是这里了
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm a little lost.
哦 对不起 我有点迷路了
Yes, I know it's your honeymoon. I apologize.
我知道你们在度蜜月呢 对不起
Go back to doing what you were doing.
你们该干什么就继续把
I'm not down here much.
我不常下来这里
It's meant to be an exit if humans ever invade.
这本来是人类入侵时 用来撤退的
So, I'm, like, the first human here, huh? That's really cool.
所以 我是第一个来这里的人类? 这真酷
Oh, boy.
哦 总算找到了
I think this is it.
我想就是这儿了
- What's happening?  - I'm terribly sorry.
- 出什么事了?  - 实在是抱歉
- My mistake.  - What is wrong with you people?
- 这是我的错  - 你们这些人有什么毛病啊?
Oh, man. This place is amazing.
哦 老兄 这地方太棒了
Okay, I could really use some silence right now.
好吧 让我耳根清净一会儿
All right, third time's a...
好的 坏事不过三...
Drac.
德库拉
Yes, Frankie?
哦 弗兰基?
Hey, buddy, what you been doing?
嘿 兄弟 你都在忙什么呢?
Don't move.
别动
Never mind that. What you been doing?
别管这个 你都在干嘛呢?
We wanted to practice our big number for Mavis's party,
我们想排练 为梅维丝的派对准备的大节目
and then these losers wouldn't get off the bandstand.
这些怂货就是不从台上下来
Okay. Put down Zombie Mozart,
把僵尸莫扎特放下
Bach and Beethoven this instant.
还有巴赫和贝多芬 马上
Did you get to rehearse at all, Zombie Beethoven?
你还用得着排练吗 僵尸贝多芬?
Listen, Drac, we wanted to play something, like old times.
听着 德库拉 我们想练一支曲子 像以前那样练
We even thought maybe you'd sing with us.
我们还想你加入
Come on, fellas. You know that I haven't sung in public since Martha.
算了把 老弟 你知道自从玛莎出事后我就不在公开场合唱歌了
Yeah, but we just thought how much, you know, Mavis would love it.
但是 我们只是觉得 梅维丝会期待你的表演
I said no!
我说了不要!
Don't ask me again!
别再问了!
Okay. Now, let's hug the zombies. Let's all make up.
好了 现在和僵尸们抱一抱 大家言归与好
- Wow. He really scared you.  - I wasn't scared.
- 哇 他真的把你唬住了  - 才没有
I was being polite, okay?
我只是有礼貌 好嘛?
Hey. What are you doing here? I thought you were planning.
嘿 你在这里干嘛呢? 我还以为你在做计划呢
I never caught your name.
我还不知道你的名字
My name's Mavis.
我叫梅维丝
Mavis? That's a pretty neat name.
梅维丝? 这名字真好听
Yeah, my mom picked it.
对我妈妈取的
So, are you going to tell me your name?
所以 你要告诉你的名字吗?
Me? My name? Good question.
我? 我叫什么? 问得好
Well, obviously, I'm Frankenstein.
明显 我叫科学怪人
No, you're not. Frankenstein is my uncle over there.
你才不是 科学怪人是我舅舅 他就在那
The gentleman hugging Zombie Mozart.
那个抱着僵尸莫扎特的先生
Right. Of course, he's your uncle.
哦 对了 他当然是你舅舅了
Well, see, I'm not "the" Frankenstein.
听着 我不是科学怪人本人
I'm his cousin, Johnnystein.
我是他的表亲科学约翰尼
- Johnnystein?  - Hey, Mavis.
- 科学约翰尼?  - 嘿 梅维丝
Who is that?
那是谁?
Are these monsters going to kill me?
这些怪物要杀我吗?
Not as long as they think you're a monster.
只要他们以为你是怪物 你就没事
Huh? That's kind of racist.
嗯? 这有点种族歧视啊
We'll talk later.
等下讨论
- Is he making fun of me?  - No, no.
- 他是在拿我开涮吗?  - 没有的事
Of course he's not, because he's...
他当然没有了 因为他是你的...
He's your cousin, Johnnystein.
表亲 科学约翰尼
Yes, yes, yes.
对对对
I don't have no cousin.
我哪来的表亲
No, no, you do. He's your sixth cousin, three times removed.
不对 你有表亲 他是你的六代表亲 搬了三次家
On your right arm's side.
跟你的右手有血缘关系
You have a cousin?
我的手有亲戚?
Frank, if your arm could talk,
弗兰克 如果你的手能说话
he would tell you that the original owner of your arm had a brother.
它就会告诉你 它本来的拥有者 有一个弟弟
Who married a woman.
跟一个女人结了婚
- Who was...  - For strangling a pig.
- 她嘛...  - 掐死了一只猪
I have pig-strangling blood in my arm?
我的手有亲戚掐死了只猪?
That's kind of cool.
听着挺酷的
Well, cuz, great to meet you.
好吧 表亲 很高兴见到你
So, what brings you here, Johnny?
你到这来干嘛 约翰尼?
- Wah! What was that?  - Oh, sorry.
- 哇! 那时什么?  - 哦 对不起
I should really clear my throat before I speak.
我该在说话前 提示性地咳一声
Anyway, what brings you here?
所以 你到底干什么来了?
Party planner.
来策划派对
Yes, I have recruited Mr. Stein here to help me with Mavis's birthday party.
对 我聘请了科学约翰尼先生来帮助我策划梅维丝的生日派对
Wait a minute, you asked someone to help you?
等等 你请人来帮你?
Captain Control Freak?
控制狂小队长?
It's Count...
是伯爵...
And yes, I thought having a Mavis contemporary would be useful.
对 我想听听梅维丝同龄人的意见
Yeah, he totally needed a fresher perspective.
是的 他急需从新鲜的视角看问题
Okay, Johnny, Mr. Tight Coffin over here
好吧约翰尼 我们的木乃伊先生
was planning to have these powdered lame-os play at the party.
准备让这些涂脂抹粉的怂货在派对上演奏
So, anyways, we thought we could liven things up a bit.
不过 怎么说 我觉得我们能把气氛炒热一些
Whoa! You all play? Let's check you guys out!
哇! 你们都上场? 露两手让我们看看!
# Girl #
# 姑娘哟 #
# I can't believe it's your big night#
# 难以置信 你今天就要成年 #
# Seems like only yesterday you were eating mosquitoes #
# 仿佛昨天 你还在吃着蚊子 #
# But now you're eating frogs and mice #
# 但是现在 青蛙 老鼠 涂点 多力多滋 #
# Scarfing them down like Doritos
# 你就吃的美滋滋 #
# Tell me #
# 告诉我 #
# Where did the time go, girl? #
# 姑娘 时光消失到了那儿? #
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on, guys.
哇 哇 等等哥几个
Stop.
停下
That's cute, but kind of old school.
曲子不错 但是太校园民谣了
Yes, thank you, Johnny.
是啊 说的好 约翰尼
You got to totally tempo things up.
节奏一定要快起来
Here, let me show you.
来 我给你们示范
Werewolf man, give me a jam!
狼人 给我起个调子!
Two, three, four!
二 三 四
# Vampire girl with the fangy fangs #
# 牙齿尖尖的吸血鬼女孩 #
# Hair real cute with the bangy bangs #
# 刘海齐齐好可爱 #
# Little princess gonna be a queen #
# 公主今天就要变女皇 #
# Legal bat lady turning 118. #
# 蝙蝠美眉就要118 #
- 118!  - Say 118!
- 118！  - 说118!
118.
Yeah! Stage dive!
耶! 来个台扑!
Awesome.
好棒
I am so blown away right now.
我现在真完全被征服了
I think my cuz is gonna make this
我想我的表亲 一定能把这个
the best party ever!
办成最好的派对!
Yeah! Maybe he can find a way to get me some chicks.
对! 也许他还能帮我找几个妞来
We should do a dance contest!
我们该办个跳舞比赛!
We're not doing any of that.
那些都没戏
We've got to stay on schedule, all right?
我们得按照计划来 懂了吗?
All right, Dad, all right.
好啦 爸爸 好啦
- Johnny, you're coming, too.  - I don't know.
- 约翰尼 你也要来  - 我不知道
- Is it cool with Dracula?  - Johnny, come with us.
- 德库拉觉得可以吗?  - 约翰尼 一起来嘛
N-27.
N-27号
G-61.
G-61号
Bingo! Bingo!
宾果! 宾果!
How dare you.
你好大的胆子
Do you know what doctor made me?
你知道我是哪个博士造出来的吗?
I didn't do that.
不是我干的
Circles?
自行车?
Fly?
苍蝇?
- Hands?  - Film.
- 手?  - 电影
- Vomit.  - The Vomit?
- 呕吐  - 叫呕吐的电影?
- The Throw Up.  - No. That wasn't a clue.
- 还是叫 吐出来  - 不是 这是无关的动作
Nothing?
什么都没有?
- Emptiness?  - Glasses?
- 空无一物?  - 眼镜?
- Glasses?  - Glasses shaking?
- 眼镜?  - 摇摇晃晃的眼镜?
Glasses shaking sideways!
把眼镜摇到一边!
Through The Looking-Glass?
透过眼镜看世界?
I stink at this.
我玩这个好烂
I didn't do that.
跟我没关系
And pull it back. And up. And push.
收回来 向上伸 再推
And twist. And back.
转体 收回来
And up. And twist.
向上 转体
And push.
再推
No. Don't copy that.
别 这个不要学
And back. And up. And twist.
收回来 向上伸 转体
Let me get a bubonic moose nose omelet
给我来个黑死病麋鹿鼻蛋卷
with cockroach paste and mouse jelly.
配上蟑螂糊糊 还有老鼠果冻
And with egg whites.
再来点蛋白
Bonjour, Monsieur
你好啊 先生
May I make you an omelet?
要我给你做个蛋卷吗?
No, no, no, no. I'm not hungry.
不 不用 我不饿
What? Esmeralda, you smell it again?
什么? 埃斯梅拉达 你又闻到了?
- Human?  - I am hungry.
- 是人味?  - 我现在饿了
Johnny, you've been to the Taj Mahal?
约翰尼 你去过泰姬陵吗?
Come on. No monster's been to the Taj.
得了吧 没怪物去过那儿
Man, I wish I could go there.
天 我多想去一次
You know what? I'll take 50 omelets.
知道吗? 给我来50个蛋卷
You heard the man! Make them!
你听到他的话了! 快去做!
How did you deal with the mobs?
遇到强盗你怎么办?
Yeah, it does get pretty crazy in the summer.
是啊 夏天他们总是特别猖獗
But, you know, you just got to roll.
不过也就跟着混呗
He just rolls. That's cool that he rolls.
就跟着混 真酷
Yes, yes, cool.
是啊 是啊 超酷
Look, love droppings, I brought you a bagel with your favorite, scream cheese.
看 宝贝 我带来了你最爱 会尖叫的芝士面包圈
Holy rabies. Thanks, Dad.
妈妈咪呀 太感谢了 老爸
Johnny, try some scream cheese, it's awesome.
约翰尼 试试这个尖叫芝士 超级好吃
Oh, cool.
哦 真有趣
But I'm scream cheese intolerant. So, polite pass.
不过我不消化会尖叫的芝士 所以 不了谢谢
Yes, of course you are.
是啊 很明显嘛
Johnny, can we party-plan talk for a minute?
约翰尼 和你商量一下派对的计划?
What are you doing?
你搞什么?
lf they find out you are human, they'll go bat poop!
让他们发现你是人类 小心把你打扁!
Relax. No one suspects anything.
放心吧 没人怀疑我
The only thing that looks weird is how much whispering you're doing.
如果他们觉得奇怪 也是因为你总偷偷摸摸的
Just wrap it up. You will say you are going in the pool and act excited.
该结束了 说你要去游泳然后装得激动点
And then you will say you hurt your back and you have to leave.
然后就说你拉伤了背要提前走
Here come good times! Whoo!
大家嗨起来! 喔!
Oh, dudes. Oh, my back.
哦 兄弟们 哦 我的背
I'm on your back!
我要坐上来!
No, no. He said, "Oh, my back."
不 不是 他是说 "哦 我的背"
- Get on my back!  - Let's do it.
- 坐上来!  - 来吧
Aw, here we go. Chicken fight! Push them off!
好 现在开始 水上斗鸡! 推到他们!
Chicken fight!
水上斗鸡!
We got you, Johnny.
你不行的 约翰尼
You're going down.
等着落水吧
Oh, yeah, we'll see, "Mavey Wavey."
哦 是嘛 等着瞧吧 梅维丝
Okay, calm down with the fight chickens!
好了 大家冷静一点!
Everyone, stop the roughhousing!
各位 别再闹了!
Whoo!
喔!
Frank, if you hurt yourself...
弗兰克 如果你伤到了...
I got it, honey.
明白了 亲爱的
The Stein boys are bred for this kind of thing.
科学怪人家的男人就是为这而生的
Geronimo!
高台跳水!
Eh-heh-heh.
咳咳咳
Kids, why'd you do that?
孩子们 怎么能这么做?
I was just in the pool.
我刚刚去游了泳
The water's cold.
水真凉啊
Don't judge me!
不许笑我!
Johnny. Your makeup.
约翰尼 你的妆
Your makeup!
你的妆啊!
Climb out. Now.
上来 快
Oh, man.
哦 天哪
l guess the Count wanted to go for a swim.
我猜伯爵也想游泳了
Cannonball!
水弹!
Oh, you messed up, baby. You messed up big time.
哦 你可给我闯祸了 宝贝 你闯了大祸了
l told you to take it down.
我告诉过你要低调
You'll ruin my hotel if they find out.
如果他们发现 我的旅店就毁了
Well, maybe you're just jealous
也许你只是嫉妒
that people are finally having fun at this place.
大家在这里终于能找点乐子了
Oh, that? That was not fun.
乐子? 那不叫乐子
Everyone running, jumping, swimming with no order.
每个人乱七八糟地 又跑又跳又游泳
That was the opposite of fun.
那一点也不像在找乐子
Do you even know what fun is?
你知道什么是乐子吗?
l invented fun!
乐子可是老子发明的!
Boy, the wrong people get to be immortal.
哎 就你也配长生不老
Look at me.
看着我
You remember nothing of this encounter.
忘掉我们曾经见面
You have no memory of this place or the monsters you met.
忘掉这个地方和你见过的怪物
Now go and never return.
现在离开 永远别回来
Wait, never return to the hotel?
等等 永远不能回旅店?
What? You were supposed to forget the hotel.
哪尼? 你应该忘掉这个旅店的
l just used my powers to erase your memory.
我明明用超能力抹去了你的记忆
l looked straight into your eyes.
我盯着你的眼睛看的
Huh. Oh, maybe it's the contact lenses.
呃 哦 可能是因为隐形眼镜
- The what?  - These little plasticky doodads
- 隐形什么?  - 这些小塑料做的便宜货
that help me see better.
能让我看清楚点
Here, let me just try and get them out real quick.
等等 我把他们拿出来 很快
Oh, that is the most disgusting thing l've ever seen!
哦 这是我见过的最恶心的动作!
- Almost got it.  - Stop doing that. Please stop doing that!
- 就好了  - 住手 拜托了 住手!
Fingers away from the eyeballs! Enough!
把手指从眼球上拿开! 够了!
Listen to me. You are never to return here.
听着 你永远都不能再回来
You are to stay away and never tell humans about this place.
你要离这里远远的 也别把这里的事告诉人类
Or I will track you down and suck every ounce of blood
不然我会找到你 吸干你
from your body until you look like a deflated whoopee cushion!
体内的每一滴血 直到你看起来像个泄气的坐垫!
Be gone.
去吧
Can't believe I'm leaving, man. That could have been so great!
竟然把我踢走 本来玩得挺好的
Dude ruined everything. Suck my blood.
那家伙把一切都毁了 想吸我的血
I should have just said, "I'm staying, old man!"
我应该说 "我就要留下 老头!"
Give him a Bruce Lee kick. Boom! Right in the...
像李小龙一样给他一脚 蹦! 对着他的...
Oh, my God. Count Dracula. Please don't kill me. I'm leaving, I'm leaving.
哦 天哪 德库拉伯爵 别杀我 我这就走 这就走
- Follow me.  - Oh. No, no, Mavis, I can't. I have to leave.
- 跟我来  - 哦 不 不 梅维丝 不行 我要走了
- You sure? It'll be fun.  - Okay.
- 真的? 很好玩哦  - 好吧
He's not gonna see me, is he?
他不会发现我吧?
Whoa.
哇
Wow, would you look at the view from up here?
哇 看这上面的景色
- You could almost see Budapest.  - Who-da-pest?
- 几乎可以看到布达佩斯(匈牙利首都)  - 乌 达 佩斯?
Is that near Ha-wi-fi?
是在夏威威附近吗?
Huh? Oh, you mean Hawaii. Yeah, that place is a knockout.
啊? 哦 你是说夏威夷吧 是啊 那里超赞的
l just went to a music festival there.
我刚去那里参加了音乐节
A human music festival?
人类的音乐节?
Uh, I believe so.
呃 我觉得是
So, did they all bite your toes and shove garlic bread in your face?
那 他们会不会想咬断你的脚趾 还拼命塞给你大蒜面包?
No. Well, one dude took a bigger bite
那倒没有 不过有个家伙
out of my energy bar than I expected,
咬了我的能量棒一大口
but I blame that on the heat.
不过应该是太热的关系
It's amazing. You've been everywhere.
好神奇呀 你哪里都去过
Well, you know, what's the alternative?
是啊 要不干什么?
Just staying at home, never exploring, never seeing what's out there?
呆在家里 足不出户 不知天下事?
I'm only gonna be 121 once, right? Got to live it.
一生只有一次121岁 对吧? 要活在当下
Yeah.
太对了
- Oh, man. The sunrise from here must be amaz...  - Ow.
- 哦 天哪 这里看日出肯定很...  - 喔
Oh, I'm sorry.
哦 对不起
Man, you've probably never even seen a sunrise, have you?
天哪 你是不是从来没见过日出?
No, not really. Why?
呃 没有 怎么?
Come on. I have an idea.
过来 我有办法了
Watch.
看
- Ahh.  - Ahh.
- 啊  - 啊
Didn't I tell you guys we'd have fun in here? Is this not the best?
告诉过你们这里好玩吧? 是不是超级有趣?
Yeah, I'm working up a nice sweat.
是啊 汗流浃背什么的是很有趣
When's that Johnny kid gonna be done party planning?
那个约翰尼的啥时候才能安排好派对呀?
- He's a great hang.  - Yeah, he's an animal.
- 超爱和他一起玩  - 是啊 他真够疯狂的
And it was so nice seeing Mavis laughing and hitting it off with him.
现在梅维丝也对他青睐有加了 真好
Who's hitting what off? Please.
谁青睐谁? 少来
Mavis could never be with someone of his kind.
梅维丝才不会和他这种类型的在一起
I'm sorry? "His kind"?
什么? "他这种类型"?
You're saying our kind's not good enough for you,
你是说我们家的孩子不够好吗
"Your Lordship"?
"陛下"?
No, no, no! Frank, I didn't...
不 不 不! 弗兰克 我没...
I meant that she wouldn't be into someone with such red, curly hair.
我是说她不会喜欢头发又红又卷的类型
Uh, what's wrong with red, curly hair?
呃 又红又卷的头发怎么了?
Why are you getting upset?
你生什么气?
I have red curly hair!
我的头发就是又红又卷的!
Well, how was I supposed to know that?
鬼才知道你长了什么毛
This is the most incredible thing l've ever seen.
这真是我见过的最美的景象
Johnny?
约翰尼?
Look, settle down, fellas.
冷静 伙计们
This is all a moot point because Johnny, he left.
还有啥意义呀 约翰尼已经走了
Wait a minute. He left?
等等 他走了?
Yes. He decided he didn't like Mavis, or any of us.
是啊 他说他不喜欢梅维丝 也不喜欢我们
Hi.
嗨
Hmm. I guess Johnny had second thoughts.
呃 看来约翰尼改变主意了
I can't believe you stuck around, man. You don't get it.
你竟然还敢留下 你还是不懂
Bad things are coming your way.
你的处境非常危险
I got... I got to get my thoughts together.
冷静 理清头绪
Okay.
好了
You see these tables?
看到这些桌子没?
You can spend the entire day pulling them out
你用这一整天把他们推出来
and placing them, party planner.
然后摆摆整齐 派对策划
Fantastic. I'm trapped here.
太棒了 我就困在这儿了
Now I know how your daughter feels.
我算是理解你女儿了
Enough! Enough! Stop!
够了! 够了! 停下来!
Go to a corner, you're in a timeout!
站在墙角 休息一下!
Timeout? I'm a grown man!
休息? 我可是个成年人!
Ahh!
啊啊啊!
Okay. Table 57, please move to position 23.
好 57号桌子 请到23号就位
Whoa.
哇
- That is cool.  - Face the wall.
- 酷毙了  - 面对墙壁
17 to 48. 16 to 47. 19 to 50.
17到48 16到47 19到50
- Awesomeness.  - Just let me do my work.
- 额滴亲娘啊  - 给我安静点
29 to 35.
29到35
42 to 18. 10 to 44.
42到18 10到44
17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23.
啊 17 18 19 20 21 22 23
39 to 24.
39到24
36 up!
36 起!
29 to 35.
29到35
Whoa!
哇
31 to 19.
31到19
24 up!
24 起!
Seven to 25. 14 to 30.
7到25 14到30
Where'd you go, grandpa?
哪去了 老大爷?
Don't freak out, gravity face.
别吓到了 重力小子
Eat my dust, gray fangs!
等着认输吧 老尖牙!
56 and 43, to my side.
56和43 到我身边来
Whoo!
喔!
Prepare to cry, Billy Backpack.
等着哭吧 小样
That's how we do it! Half-pipe, baby!
咱就是这么酷! 极限飞桌啊 宝贝!
Whatever.
还不就那样
Yes. Keep smelling.
对 就这么闻
You catch the human, and then I will make human potpie!
抓住人类 老子给你做人肉馅饼!
27, 45, 65, 76, 48, block his path.
27 45 65 76 48 挡住他
Block his path!
挡住他!
Whoa-ho!
哇哈!
Oh, come on now, dude man!
哦 别这么对我啊 伙计
Nice!
漂亮!
Haha! Whoa-ho-ho!
哈哈! 哇哈哈!
I got you, buddy.
接住你了 兄弟
Do not disturb!
请勿打扰!
People trying to sleep here!
有人睡着呢!
Did you see that?
看到了吗?
Who is that guy, Sir Breaks-a-lot?
那家伙是谁呀 霹雳侠吗?
Oh, boy, I have to say, that was fun. Okay?
哦 天哪 我承认 真好玩 是吧?
The fun you were talking about earlier? Nailed it!
你之前不是说乐子吗? 名不虚传!
Johnny?
约翰尼?
Quasimodo!
卡西莫多!
Mavis? Why are you still up? The sun is out. It could kill you, my honeyguts.
梅维丝? 你怎么还不睡? 太阳出来了 会伤着你的 我的心肝
l couldn't sleep. Do you know where Johnny went?
睡不着 知道约翰尼在哪吗?
I don't know. He...
不知道 他...
- Why do you want to know?  - Oh! Uh...
- 你知道这干嘛?  - 哦 呃...
- Do you like him?  - What?
- 你喜欢他?  - 什么?
Pfft, no. Come on, Dad. He's so weird and awkward.
切 才不 拜托了 老爸 他又奇怪又笨
It's like, are you an idiot or do you know you're adorable?
都不知道他是真笨还是太可爱?
Eh... Hold that.
呃... 等等
- Do you have a location on Quasimodo?  - Yes, sir.
- 知道卡西莫多的确切位置吗?  - 是的 先生
They're heading through the lobby, towards the kitchen.
他们正要穿过大厅 去往厨房
I need them stopped immediately.
让他们立刻停下来
- Is that clear?  - Yes, quite.
- 听清楚了没?  - 非常清楚
We are on it.
我们马上去办
Ha-ha! Missed!
哈哈! 没打着!
What is the meaning of this? Let me pass!
你们这是干什么? 让我过去!
Quasimodo Wilson, you are coming with us.
卡西莫多·威尔逊 跟我们走
Why did that hurt me?
我咋会痛呢?
Look, honey, there's no falling in love at your age.
听着 宝贝 你才多大啊 还不懂爱情呢
Mom was my age. Eunice says Mom kissed you first
妈妈当时就这么大啊 尤尼斯说妈妈先亲的你
'cause you were too scared to make the first move.
因为你不敢对她动手动脚
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
是 是 是 是 是 是
Forget about me and Mom and kissing.
别提我和你妈还有什么亲嘴了
Dad, at some point, I'm going to get married.
爸爸 总有一天 我会要结婚的
- I can't be here forever.  - What? Why not?
- 我不能一辈子呆在这里  - 什么? 为啥不能?
You're barely out of your training fangs.
你还没脱牙套呢
Ha-ha!
哈 哈!
Quasi wins again!
我又赢了!
When you bump with the hump, you land on your rump!
一拳下去 屁屁着地!
But why all the sudden interest?
你怎么突然感兴趣了?
Every time we used to talk about love, it was always,
每次我们谈到爱情 你总说
"Ooh, Dad, that's gross,"
"哦 爸爸 真恶心耶"
and "Ooh, Dad, I don't want to know about that."
或者 "哦 爸爸 我不要知道这些啦"
I don't know.
我也不知道
- Sir, he made it into the kitchen.  - He what?
- 先生 他到厨房去了  - 他什么?
What do I pay you for?
你是干什么吃的?
I'm sorry, honey. I have to go.
对不起 宝贝 我要走了
He doesn't pay me.
我啥也没吃
Before you kill me,
在你杀我之前
can I please talk to my backpack one more time?
能不能让我给背包留个遗言?
I don't want to leave anything unresolved.
我不想就这么丢下它
Bonjour, Monsieur Dracula.
你好 德库拉先生
Shut your hump hole.
闭上你的臭嘴
Now you are helping him?
你要帮他?
What is it with you and this human?
你到底和这人类是啥关系?
He is not human. He's a Stein!
他不是人类 他是科学怪人家的人!
That's right, little man, I'm a Stein!
是啊 矮子 我是科学怪人家的
If he is a monster, let him scare Esmeralda!
如果他是怪兽 让他吓吓埃斯梅拉达!
The mouse?
那只老鼠?
Pfft! Without a doubt.
切! 小意思
Okay. Here we go.
好吧 看我的
Blargh!
呃啊!
Bleegh!
呃哦!
Blargy-bliggy-blargh!
呃啊 呃哦 呃啊!
A human! A human!
人类! 是人类!
Monsieur has brought a human into the...
先生把人类带进了...
Esmeralda, help me.
埃斯梅拉达 帮帮我
Hey, thanks for saving me back there.
嘿 多谢你救我
That guy's crazy! Trying to eat me.
那家伙疯了 想吃掉我
That's only happened to me one other time. This weird dude at a Slipknot concert.
这事只发生过一次 在活结乐队的演唱会上有个怪蜀黍
There's something I need to show you.
我要给你看样东西
Wow.
喔
Hey, are we at a funeral right now?
嘿 我们在参加葬礼吗?
Oh, wait, no, it's your bed.
哦 等等 不是 这是你的床
So creepy and cool.
爽得让人脊梁发冷啊
Wow! I know her!
喔! 我知道她!
l've seen that picture at the ruins of Lubov. That's my favorite castle.
我在爱之堡的废墟里见过这张照片 那是我最爱的城堡
There's a whole legend around that lady.
据说那女人有一段传奇故事
A legend?
传奇故事?
The Lady Lubov.
爱之女士
The story is that a lonely count
故事讲的是一个孤独的伯爵
met her by chance, and they say that no two souls
偶遇了她 人们都说从未见过
were ever more meant for each other.
如此心心相印的两个人
Eventually, they settled down at Castle Lubov and had a child.
最后 他们安顿在爱之堡 也有了孩子
But then, a horrible tragedy happened.
不过后来 可怕的悲剧发生了
A fire started mysteriously one night, and it killed both of them.
那晚 一场神秘的大火烧死了他们
When I was at the castle, I could still feel their powerful love.
当我走进城堡 仍能感受到他们摄人心魄的爱情
They say it's as if a soul is still trapped in the ruins themselves.
人们说 就好像有一个灵魂仍被困在他们的残骸当中
The legend is wrong.
你的故事错了
It was only the wife that died.
只有妻子死在大火里
Oh.
哦
And it was no mystery who killed her.
她的死因一点也不神秘
She was killed by your kind!
她是被你们人类烧死的!
Vampire!
吸血鬼!
- Honey?  - Go hide. I'll take care of this.
- 亲爱的?  - 去藏起来 我来处理
Vampire!
吸血鬼!
Martha!
玛莎!
They are the real monsters.
他们才是真正的鬼怪
I built this place for my love, to protect her child.
我为了我的爱人 保护我的孩子建造这屋宇
As a father, you do everything to keep your family safe,
身为人父 会为了保护家庭赴汤蹈火
even if you have to break their trust.
即便失去他们对你的信任也在所不辞
But now, Mavis has feelings for you.
可现在 梅维丝喜欢上了你
What?
什么?
I... I just...
我... 我只是...
- Awesome.  - It's all right.
- 好极了  - 没事的
You are a good one.
你是个好人
lf the world was different, maybe it would be possible.
如果世界不一样了 也许你们还有可能
Drac, this is the 21st century.
德库拉 这都21世纪了
People aren't the same as they were back then.
人们已经和以前不一样了
Can you tell me for certain that if we came out in the open,
你确定 如果我们公开自己的身份
everyone would accept us?
每个人都会接纳我们?
Everyone?
每个人?
No. You're right.
好吧 你没说错
I'll go for good this time.
这次我会永远不会回来了
You can just say I had some emergency,
你就说我有点急事
or the gremlin lady ate me or something.
或者我被一个小精灵吃掉了之类的
No, no, no, no, no.
不 不 不 不 不
I don't want to ruin her birthday party.
我不想搞砸她的生日派对
You can sneak out after it's all done.
你可以在结束了之后溜走
I'm sorry.
抱歉
The last thing I wanted was to hurt her.
我不想伤害她
Or you.
还有你
You know, you're not the smoothest Frankenstein,
其实 你扮科学怪人没有天分
but you'd make a great vampire.
可你会是一个好吸血鬼
For real?
真的?
'Cause I think I kind of got your hypno-eyes down.
我就说我有一双催眠眼
Oh, boy, here we go. Let me see it.
哦 天哪 好吧 让我看看
Beware! For you are in my power.
小心! 因为你在我统治之下
I command you to be the werewolf man!
我命令你成为狼人!
I have too many kids.
我有好几个孩子呢
Someone scratch me, I have fleas.
给我挠挠 我有虱子
'Cause he's a wolf, he'd get those.
因为他是狼人 狼人有虱子
Yeah, no, don't explain it.
是啊 别 别解释
It's not funny when you do that.
解释就不好玩了
I didn't order a wake-up call.
我又没订唤醒服务
Count Dracula arranged it for all the rooms.
德库拉伯爵给每个房间都订了
Where's the snooze button?
那个打盹的按钮呢?
There will be no snoozing. The party's today.
不能打盹 派对是今天
Ooh, yeah, perfecto.
哦 就这样 好极了
118岁生日快乐——妈妈
# Girl #
# 姑娘哟 #
# I can't believe it's your big night #
# 难以置信 你今天就要成年 #
# You ate your frogs, now the party's so right #
# 到吃青蛙的年纪 到疯狂派对的时间 #
# Where did the time go, girl? #
# 姑娘 时光消失到了哪儿 #
# And, girl, you used to suck a binky #
# 姑娘 你曾经只能吸兔子的血 #
# Look at you now #
# 看看现在 #
# You're sucking blood right out of the cow #
# 你已能制服一整头牛 #
Wow.
哇
You look beautiful.
你真美
Thanks. Thanks for the party.
谢谢 谢谢你办的派对
Yeah, you like my little touches?
是啊 喜欢我的小魔术吗?
巴黎
纽约
莫斯科
夏威威
It's amazing.
太神奇了
- Terrific party.  - You really outdid yourself, Drac.
- 派对真棒  - 你可真是超越了自己啊 德库拉
Got to be the best one l've been to in 500 years.
这是我500年来参加过的最好的派对
Sorry, big man.
抱歉 巨人
Uh, Mavis?
呃 梅维丝?
I'm crazily scared right now.
我现在超级害怕
Maybe that's a good thing.
可能这是件好事
How could you? After I shared my pain with you?
你怎么能这样? 我还和你分享了我的痛苦?
- But, no...  - Dad, it was just a kiss.
- 可 不是...  - 爸爸 只是接吻而已啦
No, you're not allowed to kiss.
不 你不可以接吻
Dad, I'm allowed to do things. I'm not 38 anymore.
爸爸 我可以做任何事 我不是38岁的孩子了
I'm allowed to like people, or go see the world again.
我可以喜欢别人 或者去看看外面的世界
What? You saw it! You said you didn't like it!
什么? 你看到了! 你说你不喜欢那里!
Maybe I want to give the village another chance.
也许我想去村庄再试一次
l just need to learn, you know, just how to roll with it, like Johnny does.
我只是需要学习 知道怎么随波逐流 就像约翰尼这样
No, no, you can't go to the village again.
不 不 你不能再去那个村庄了
Maybe you can make them see that we could be friends.
也许你能让他们知道 我们可以做朋友呢
No, that isn't possible.
不 那不可能
Well, you can't be sure. It's all in how you present yourself.
你凭什么这么肯定 只是看你怎么展示自己罢了
- No, that won't make a difference!  - How do you know?
- 不 根本没用  - 你怎么知道?
- Because it just won't!  - Why? Why won't it?
- 就因为没用! -为什么?为什么没用?
Because that village doesn't really exist!
因为那村庄根本不存在!
What do you mean "doesn't exist"?
什么叫"不存在"?
What did you do?
你做了什么?
l did what I had to do.
我只是做了我必须做的事
What was it?
是什么?
What exactly did you have to do? Tell me!
你到底做了什么? 告诉我!
I... I built the town. The staff put it all together.
我... 我建了那个小镇 那些人是我弄来的
The zombies dressed up as the townspeople.
僵尸们扮演了镇上的人
Please. I...
别生气 我...
If you really went out there and something happened to you,
如果你真的在外面遇到什么危险
I just couldn't live with myself.
我肯定不能原谅自己
But you can live with this? Lying to me? Tricking me?
但是你能原谅自己这样做? 对我说谎? 骗我?
Keeping me here forever when you knew my dream was to go.
尽管你知道我梦想着离开 但还是要把我永远留在这里
Liar! Liar!
骗子! 骗子!
Oil?
是邋遢厨子?
Uh... uh... uh!
唔... 啊... 啊!
English, please.
请说英语
Your voice is really annoying.
你的声音太烦人了
Wait, I speak frozen.
稍等 我来做翻译
He says, "Dracula has brought a human into the hotel."
他说 "德库拉把一个人类带进了旅馆"
- A human?  - Stay close, Pookie!
- 一个人类?  - 快过来 小甜心！
He says, "There is ze human."
他说 "人类在辣里"
He has a French accent.
他说话有法国腔
Johnny's not a human. He's my right arm's cousin.
约翰尼不是人类 他是我右手那边的堂弟
- He's lying.  - Yeah.
- 他在说谎  - 是啊
And why is he picking his nose?
而且他为什么在挖鼻孔?
He says, "It's a long story."
他说 "这就说来话长了"
Hey, wait, no! Get off me!
嘿 等下 别! 放开我!
Ew!
哎呦!
He says, "Behold ze human."
他说 "看啊 辣就是人类"
I don't believe it.
真不敢相信
Is it true? Are you a human?
是真的吗? 你是人类吗?
Yes.
是
I'm so sorry.
我真的很抱歉
I don't care. I still want to be with you.
我不在乎 我还是想和你在一起
Uh...
呃..
Well, tough. Because I don't want to be with you.
还是算了吧 因为我并不想和你在一起
Because you're a monster. And I hate monsters.
因为你是个怪物 而我讨厌怪物
Goodbye.
再见了
Please don't hurt me!
请别伤害我!
This is all your fault!
这一切都怪你!
- We're getting out of here.  - I'm never coming back here.
- 我们要离开这里  - 我再也不会来这里了
- I thought I smelt a human.  - "Human-free"? What a rip.
- 我早就觉得闻到了人类的味道  - "绝无人类"? 真是胡说
Oh. Here he comes. Count Crock-ula.
哦 骗子伯爵来了
I'm just glad my eyes are stitched shut, because I don't even want to...
我真高兴我的眼睛瞎了 因为我可不想...
Mavis, honey, are you in there?
梅维丝 宝贝 你在里面吗?
Mavis? Mavis?
梅维丝? 梅维丝你在哪?
Mavis, where are you?
梅维丝 你去哪了?
Mavis?
梅维丝 你在哪?
Dad, can you do me a favor?
爸 能帮我个忙吗?
Yes, yes, of course, darling. Anything.
可以 当然可以 亲爱的 干什么都行
Will you erase my mind?
你能消除我的记忆吗?
No, no, no, no. No, I won't do that.
不 不 这可不行 我不会那么做的
There's too much I want you to remember.
有许多事情是我希望你记得的
You were right, Dad. The humans hate us.
你说得对 老爸 人类讨厌我们
Sweetheart, there are so many eligible monsters out there.
宝贝 其实也有许多不错的怪物男孩
You're so young to...
你也还年轻...
What is it? What are you reading?
那是什么? 你在看什么?
True Love by Mom
真爱 妈妈著
For your 118th birthday
献给你的118岁生日
"Two lonely bats crashed in the night.
"两只寂寞的蝙蝠 在黑夜里相遇
"They felt a Zing. Love at first sight.
"他们怦然心动 一见钟情
"They knew right then they would be husband and wife.
"那时起 他们便知道彼此将要结为夫妻
"For a Zing only happens once in your life.
"因为一生中只会有一次心动
"Your Zing will come, my love.
"亲爱的 让你心动的人也会出现的
"Cherish it.
"一定要珍惜"
"Love, Mommy."
"爱你的妈妈"
- I thought we Zinged, Dad.  - You and Johnny?
- 我觉得我们动心了 爸  - 你和约翰尼?
I guess it was only me.
我想只有我动心了
But you should be happy, Dad.
不过你可以放心了 爸
There's no reason for me to leave.
我再也没有离开的理由了
I have no more dreams. I'm just like you now.
也没有梦想了 我现在就和你一样
PARADISE you can find it all in Hawaii
天堂 你可以在夏威夷找到它
Martha, what have I done?
玛莎 我做了什么
- Where is my bill?  - Over here. I'm next.
- 我的账单呢?  - 在这呢 我是下一个
- I'm checking out.  - Take my key! Take my key!
- 我要退房  - 拿走我的钥匙! 给你!
What is this minibar charge?
这个迷你冰箱费用是怎么回事?
Honey, the kids threw the minibar out the window.
亲爱的 孩子们把迷你冰箱扔到了窗户外面
- And that's our fault?  - Well...
- 这难道是我们的错?  - 这个...
Excuse me! Pardon, yeah.
让一下! 不好意思
Excuse me, I got a couple of people to express mail.
不好意思 有几个人需要快递
Friends, please, stop.
朋友们 拜托了 停下来
It's too late, rat-bat!
太晚了 臭蝙蝠!
Please, I'm begging you.
拜托 我求你们了
I need you to help me find Johnny.
我需要你们帮我找到约翰尼
The human? He could've killed us!
那个人类? 他可能会杀了我们!
He touched my guitar!
他摸过我的吉他!
He put his hand in my mouth to see if it would disappear.
他把手伸进我嘴里 看它们会不会消失
He let me eat his scooter!
他让我吃了他的滑板!
I know I lied.
我知道我说谎了
I was wrong.
我错了
But you have to believe this:
但是你们要相信
Johnny wasn't a bad guy.
约翰尼不是坏人
The truth is, I don't even know if humans are bad anymore.
事实上 我也不知道人类是不是依然邪恶
Frank, come on, buddy. You understand.
弗兰克 别这样 老兄 你懂我的
He's not talking to you.
他不会再跟你说话
First you tell us humans are bad, now they're good.
你先告诉我们人类都很坏 现在他们又变好了
What else? Up is down, cold is hot, Gremlins don't smell.
还有什么? 上就是下 冷就是热 精灵没有嗅觉
Hey!
嘿!
I really liked Johnny, cousin or no. He told fun stories.
我真的很喜欢约翰尼 不管他是不是我堂弟 他会讲好玩的故事
I think they Zinged.
我觉得他们一见钟情了
They Zinged?
他们一见钟情?
But I got in the way.
但是我阻碍了他们
You only Zing once in your life.
一生中只会动心一次
- Oy, now you're short-circuiting.  - I don't care!
- 喂 你现在短路了  - 我无所谓!
Well, what are we doing? Let's get Johnny. Come on!
那我们还等什么? 去找约翰尼吧 来吧!
- Yeah, let's do it!  - Come on!
- 是啊 就这么干  - 来啊!
Yeah!
好啊!
We should have honeymooned at your parents!
我们应该在你父母家度蜜月的!
Okay, okay, where am I going?
好吧 好吧 我要去哪里?
The human world, before Johnny's gone forever.
人类世界 在约翰尼永远离开之前
But what about the sun?
那太阳怎么办?
I don't know. I'll just have to roll.
我不知道 我大概得跟着混了
He just rolls. Rollability.
他跟着混 他可以的
So we follow his boot-prints.
我们跟着他的脚印走
When they run out, that's where you come in, Wayne.
当它们消失的时候 你就派上用场了 韦恩
- Me?  - There!
- 我?  - 那里!
Yes, I knew something would fall out of that backpack.
对 我就知道背包里一定会掉出来点东西
Yowch! That stinks!
嗷! 简直是恶臭!
Work your magic.
快用你的魔法
Wait, you want me to track the smell?
等下 你想让我追寻这股气味?
No. My sniffing tracking days are way behind me.
不行 我的嗅觉跟踪功力早就不行了
Do you know how many diapers I've changed?
你知道我换过多少块尿布吗?
How many number twos have destroyed this thing?
你知道那些便便早就毁了我的鼻子吗?
But...
不过...
Hey! Take it easy! Watch it!
嘿! 别着急! 小心!
Sit.
坐下
Smell. I said smell.
闻一下 我让你们闻一下
Not me, the shirt! The shirt!
不是我 是汗衫! 汗衫!
Do any of your kids still respect you?
你的孩子们当中还有谁听你的话吗?
Mm, give me a second. Oh, yeah.
呃 稍等 哦 对了
Winnie! Front and center!
维妮! 到前面来!
He got into a car. An 86 Fiat.
他上了一辆车 是86年产的菲亚特
It needs a little transmission work, but otherwise okay.
那辆车变速器需要修理 不过不修也没事
It drove through town to the airport. Flight 497.
它开向城里的机场 497号航班
8:00 a.m. departure.
上午八点起飞
That's in 15 minutes.
还有15分钟
Seat 23A.
座位号是23A
He ordered the vegetarian meal.
他订了素食餐点
Okay, thank you, cutie.
好的 谢谢你 小可爱
Now, all of you, go back to your mother!
现在 你们全都回到妈妈身边!
Sheep!
有只羊!
High five! Don't leave me hanging.
太棒了! 别让我在外面挂着
- Lots of sheep!  - I got this one.
- 好多羊!  - 我来解决它们
What? Now there's no sheep in the road. Let's go.
怎么了? 现在路上没有羊了 走吧
That was pretty sick, man.
这有点恶心 老兄
You eat lamb chops, it's the same thing.
你也吃羊排 没什么区别
We don't have time for this. Come on, let's move it!
我们没时间说这个了 快点 开车!
Look, a human.
看 有个人!
Welcome to Transylvania!
欢迎来到精灵旅社！
That was trippy.
我有点晕了
Monster Festival?
怪物节?
What's a Monster Festival?
什么是怪物节?
We love Dracula
我们爱德库拉
I carry a torch for Frankenstein
我为科学怪人举火把
Did they know we were coming?
他们早知道我们要来?
They like us?
他们喜欢我们?
Really?
真的?
Excuse me? Do you know the best way to the airport?
打扰一下 你知道去机场最快的路线吗?
Yes, fellow Dracula. There's only one way. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
知道 德库拉老兄 只有那一条路 哇啊啊
But it's all blocked. We'll never make it in time.
但是路被堵住了 我们不可能及时赶到的
You should have left an hour earlier. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
你应该提前一小时出来的 哇啊啊
I do not say "Bleh, bleh-bleh."
我从来不说"哇啊啊"
All right, let's just run through it on foot.
好吧 我们跑过去吧
Drac, this'll protect you.
德库拉 这个会保护你的
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
哇啊啊
Imagine if that guy knew he was talking to the real Drac,
想象一下 如果那个人知道他是在和真的德库拉说话
he'd run for the hills!
他会吓的跑得远远的!
Hold it, now. Hold it, now.
等一下 等一下
That sounds spot on.
这可说到点上了
But the only way they'd know the real us is if we show the real us.
不过只有我们展示出来我们是真的 他们才会知道
This could work.
这个办法不错
You mean, like, scare them? We haven't scared people in centuries.
你是说 比如 吓唬他们? 我们都有几个世纪没吓唬过人类了
I don't even think I have it in me anymore.
我甚至都不觉得我还知道怎么吓唬人
I got nothing. I really got nothing.
我不会了 我真的什么都不会了
Let's just move this along.
只要划一下火柴就好了
Fire! Fire!
火! 火!
Fire!
火!
I'm trying to scare you!
我在吓唬你们!
The real Frankenstein!
我是真正的科学怪人！
We know! We love you!
我们知道! 我们爱你!
Can you sign my torch?
你能在我的火把上签个名吗?
Listen, before anything else, down there's the real Dracula!
听着 说正事之前 我先告诉大家那位是真正的德库拉!
Prove it.
能证明吗?
All right. Continue.
好吧 继续
Drac's daughter's in love, and he's got to get to the airport!
德库拉的女儿坠入爱河了 而他需要赶到机场!
And he can't get through this crowd!
但他没法穿过人海!
- Why doesn't he fly?  - The sun, you idiot. He's a vampire.
- 他为什么不飞过去?  - 因为太阳 你个笨蛋 他是吸血鬼
That's right. Thank you, Monster Nerd.
说得好 谢谢你 书呆子怪物
So, people, if you really are our friends, clear a path for the man!
那么 如果你们真的是我们的朋友 请为他让出一条路来!
Okay. All Draculas, line up. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
好吧 所有吸血鬼 列队 哇啊啊
Everyone else, lift the capes. Protect our friend. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
其他人拉起斗篷 保护我们的朋友 哇啊啊
It's all for you, buddy.
这都是为了你 老兄
Go ahead.
去吧
- Good luck!  - Go get them!
- 祝你好运!  - 去找到他们!
Go, Drac, go!
快 德库拉 快!
- Go, Drac!  - Go, Drac!
- 去吧 德库拉!  - 快 德库拉!
Go, Drac!
加油 德库拉!
快点 德库拉!
Go, Drac!
去吧 德库拉!
Go get them!
去找他们吧!
Go, Drac, go!
快点 德库拉!
We love you, Dracula!
我们爱你 德库拉!
There's no choice.
别无选择了
Ouch. Ouch, ouch, ouch.
嗷 嗷 嗷 嗷
Okay. Okay, I must do this.
好吧 我必须这么做
Jonathan. Jonathan, can you hear me?
约翰尼 约翰尼 你能听见我说话吗?
Tell me, do you dream of being a vampire?
告诉我 你想变成吸血鬼吗?
This is how we're represented. Unbelievable.
他们就是这样描写我们的 难以置信
Jonathan. Jonathan.
嘿 约翰尼
Can you hear me?
你能听见吗?
Whoa! Bat!
哇! 蝙蝠!
Wait, it's talking. Dracula? Is that you?
等下 它在说话 德库拉? 是你吗?
Huh? Dracula.
什么? 德库拉
I can't understand you.
我听不见你说话
What? My hand's in a tan shoe?
什么? 棕色皮鞋里有我的爪子?
What? Japan's eating lamb stew?
什么? 日本在吃炖羊扒?
Hey, do you know you're smoking?
嘿 你知道你在冒烟吗?
Oh.
哦
Pardon me. Sorry, excuse me.
对不起 不好意思
Whoa! Excuse me.
啊 对不起
- What the heck?  - How'd a bat get up this high?
- 这是什么鬼东西?  - 蝙蝠怎么能飞这么高?
Folks, I'm gonna turn on the seat belt sign. Just a precaution while we...
乘客朋友们 我将点亮安全带指示灯 只是为了防止在我们...
While we hear a special announcement for my dear friend Jonathan.
听到一段特别声明的过程中出现意外 这是为我的朋友约翰尼准备的
Dracula?
是德库拉?
My dear boy, I have made a terrible mistake.
我亲爱的的孩子 我犯了严重的错误
I was trying to keep my baby to myself,
我试着让我的宝贝女儿呆在我身边
because I knew I would always protect her.
因为我以为 我可以一直保护她
But I realize now, children need to discover things for themselves.
但我现在意识到 孩子们需要自己去探索
They'll stumble and fall, laugh and cry,
他们会跌倒 会摔跤 这过程中有笑有泪
but such is life.
但这就是生活
The truth is, you and Mavis are meant to be.
事实上 你和梅维丝是天生一对
You Zinged.
你们一见钟情
If she must give her trust to someone else,
如果她除了我之外必须信任另外的人
I'm thankful that it is you, Jonathan.
那我很高兴那人是你 约翰尼
I hope you can hear me and forgive me.
我希望你能听见我说话并且原谅我
Okay, folks, we're going to make a quick turnaround to refuel,
好了 乘客朋友们 我们将马上调头回去加油
and then we'll be back on our way.
之后我们将正常航行
Quit your whining! I'm burning up out here!
别抱怨了! 我身上都着火了!
Dad?
爸?
I'm fine. I'm just a little sunburnt.
我没事 有点晒伤而已
Honey,
亲爱的
I always thought the worst thing ever would be seeing you go.
我一直以为最糟糕的是就是看着你离开
But the worst is seeing you unhappy.
但是最糟的是看见你不开心
Mavey, I want you to live your life.
梅维丝 我想让你拥有属于自己的生活
I don't know how I'm supposed to do that.
我不知道该怎么做
You know, Mommy already gave you her birthday present.
你知道的 你妈妈已经送给你生日礼物了
Can I now give you mine?
现在给你我的礼物好吗?
What do I need this for?
我要这个有什么用?
Oh, it comes with an accessory.
哦 它还有个配件
- You?  - You.
- 是你?  - 是你
Why are you back?
你怎么回来了?
Because you're my Zing, Mavis.
因为你是我的梦中情人 梅维丝
I'm your Zing?
我是你的梦中情人?
But you told me you hate monsters.
但是你说你讨厌怪物
Yeah, well, I was afraid your dad was gonna
是 因为当时我害怕如果我不那么说
suck all the blood out of my body if I didn't say that.
你爸爸就会吸干我的血
I wouldn't have...
我才不会...
No, he's right, I would have done that.
不 他说得对 我会那么干的
- Dad.  - I was wrong, Devil-chops.
- 爸  - 我错了 我认定他们都很坏
Do you really mean it, Dad?
你真的同意 老爸?
Go make your own paradise.
去创造你们自己的天堂吧
Can we try that kiss over again?
我可以试着重新亲你一次吗?
I think we can.
我想可以
Sorry. I just... I got to get used to that.
对不起 我只是... 我得学着习惯这个
Go. Do your thing.
继续 做你们的事吧
Happy Birthday Mavis
祝梅维丝生日快乐
Stop! Stop!
停! 停!
# I thought I found a love but she was just a fling #
# 我以为我找到了真爱 但那只是幻影 #
# And then I met a girl and felt a different thing #
# 后来遇到一个女孩 我发现不同的事情 #
# It's like you're hit in the ring Like you're pulled by a string #
# 就好像是被击中 被绳子拽着前行 #
# Can't breathe like you're choking on a chicken wing #
# 我无法呼吸 就像骨头卡住脖颈 #
# It was a thing called a Zing and I wanted to sing #
# 这感觉是一见钟情 让我唱给你听 #
# And listen to ballads of the man named Sting #
# 一起聆听那首小调 它来自斯汀 #
# Lady looks in your eyes and it's suddenly spring #
# 看着你的眼睛 就好像是春天已经来临 #
# Like when Nala looked at Simba in The Lion King #
# 就像狮子王里 当娜娜看着辛巴的眼睛 #
# Zinging in the air and I don't have a care #
# 我竟然没察觉到爱情的来临 #
# I'm winging from the Zing that we shared #
# 自由翱翔在我们的爱情中 #
# Zinging in the rain now I'm feeling no pain #
# 在雨中相爱 没有丝毫伤痛 #
# It's a real time for celebrating #
# 让我们一起庆祝这一刻 #
# Because you're my Zing #
# 因为我们的爱是命中注定 #
Drac, you ready to throw down?
德库拉 你准备来下面加入我们吗?
No, no, I just came closer to hear you better.
不 不 我来前面只是想听得更清楚
Come on, just give it a try.
来吧 试一下
All right, maybe just a little.
好吧 试一下也行
# So listen all you Zingers from here to Beijing #
# 不管朋友你来自哪里 都一定要听清 #
# You better crash the box spring get ready to cling #
# 你最好跳下蹦床 站稳扶好别太吃惊 #
# Because if love was money you'd be yelling cha-ching #
# 假如爱情即金钱 你们会往银行跑不停 #
# Next to a Zing Cupid's arrow's a little bee sting #
# 丘比特的爱神之箭 也会让人有点疼 #
# It was a Zing and a zang and a zingidy-dee #
# 这感觉就叫做 就叫做一见钟情 #
# And there was only one lady in the Zing for me #
# 这世上让我动心的 只有她一个女生 #
# Because when you're dinged by the Zing #
# 因为当你遇到爱 #
# You better know one thing the only bling you gonna sling #
# 你要懂得一件事情 你将要拿起的闪亮首饰 #
# Is a wedding ring #
# 是一枚戒指 #
# Zinging in the air #
# 爱情已经来临 #
# Now I don't have a care #
# 让我不顾一切 #
# I'm winging from the Zing that we shared #
# 在我们的爱中自由翱翔 #
# Zinging in the rain now I'm feeling no pain #
# 相爱在雨中 没有丝毫伤痛 #
# It's a real time for celebrating #
# 让我们来庆祝此刻 #
# Because you're my Zing #
# 因为我们的爱是命中注定 #
# Feel the Zing, y'all Ba-da-bing, y'all #
# 所有的人 感觉到爱 #
# Gonna knock you right out of that ring, y'all #
# 那枚戒指 让你震惊 #
# Better bring, y'all happening, y'all #
# 你们最好带上它 好事要发生 #
# Pay attention to the undead king, y'all #
# 你们都要注意看我这个不死之王 #
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 旺仔仔 发条橙 Gabriella 凤梨酥
校对: 柚子茶 月光取暖
# I'm a monster I'm a m-monster #
# 我是怪物 我是怪怪物 #
Housekeeping!
客房服务!
# I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love #
# 我独一无二 大家都喜欢 #
# And I don't have to try, I just do what I does #
# 我不用强求 只是随心所欲 #
# Don't have to tell me, I already know #
# 不要告诉我 我已经明白 #
# They all want me #
# 大家都把我来爱 #
# Yo, I run this, I smash it #
# 呦 我经营它 又打破它 #
# Like my bass real hard, boom-bastic #
# 就像我的贝斯一样坚强到爆炸 #
# Speed race, baby, I'm a lot faster #
# 和我赛跑 宝贝 我能更快 #
# Cause trouble, never listen to my master #
# 爱惹麻烦 从来不听 老板的话 #
# New Benz all black from Malaysia #
# 新的奔驰 黑色那辆 来自马来西亚 #
# Can't drive, but my mama don't care, yup #
# 我不能看车 不过我妈妈不在乎啊 耶 #
# To the top, I'm take it to the ceiling #
# 一路向上 我到了房顶 #
# I'm on the moon but I feel the sun beaming #
# 站在月亮上 但我怕太阳 #
# I'm so dope like ooh la la so, so fly like a helicopter #
# 我过于兴奋 想跳草裙舞 飞起来就好像 直升机降临 #
# Sup to the hood and the homies on the block #
# 让流浪人吃饭 他的同乡来堵住街道 我无法前行 #
# Doing it big, yeah, you know, what's up #
# 把事情做大 耶 这你懂的 怎么了 #
# Some come and try to say I'm a problem #
# 有人来这说我是个麻烦 #
# So crazy, gotta put them in an asylum #
# 太疯狂了 他们都应该去疯人院 #
# Some come and try to say I'm a problem #
# 有人来这说我是个麻烦 #
# Ha, solve it #
# 哈 解决掉他 #
# I'm a monster, I'm a m-monster #
# 我是怪物 我是怪怪物 #
# I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love #
# 我独一无二 大家都喜欢 #
# And I don't have to try, I just do what I does #
# 我不用强求 只随心所欲 #
# Don't have to tell me, I already know #
# 不用告诉我 我已经明白 #
# They all want me #
# 大家都把我来爱 #
# Yo, yo, yo #
# 呦 呦 呦 #
# I ran this, I rock this #
# 我经营它 我唱摇滚 #
# I can see the future, no optics #
# 我看得到未来 我别无选择 #
# More androids, robotics #
# 还有更多机器人 机器人 #
# Beam up hot chicks like I'm Spock #
# 让美女围在我身边 就好像我是斯波克 #
# They be chilling in my cockpit my spaceship got exotic #
# 他们在我的座舱里兴奋得发抖 我的飞船有异域来客 #
# One be tripping, come and whip, hypnotic #
# 有个人被绊倒 她过来打我 我就把她催眠了 #
# They be talking 'bout ooh la la #
# 她们会聊关于草裙舞的事情 #
# Let's go far, way past them stars #
# 让我们远行 超越群星 #
# We don't give up let's go to Mars #
# 我们从不放弃 我们去火星 #
# Ay, yo I'm just trying to get it popping #
# 啊 呦 我只是想让这成为潮流 #
# I wanna be the first dude to love a Martian #
# 我想成为第一个爱上火星美女的人 #
# She'll have a maid for the swag that I'm dropping #
# 她若需要一个人帮她去拎包 那么我愿效劳 #
# I kill the game til it's chilling in the coffin #
# 我能杀死猎物 让它在棺材里颤抖 #
# When I start, there ain't no stopping #
# 我一旦开始 就不会轻易停手 #
# Don't be acting like Like you didn't know #
# 别装作 装作什么都不知道 #
# Like you didn't know Like you didn't know #
# 就像你不知道 就像你不知道 #
# Like you didn't know #
# 就像你不知道 #
# I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love #
# 我独一无二 大家都喜欢 #
# And I don't have to try, I just do what I does #
# 我不用强求 只是随心所欲 #
# Don't have to tell me, I already know #
# 不用告诉我 我已经明白 #
# They all want me #
# 大家都把我来爱 #
# I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love #
# 我独一无二 大家都喜欢 #
# And I don't have to try, I just do what I does #
# 我不用强求 我只是随心所欲 #
# Don't have to tell me, I already know #
# 不用告诉我 我已经明白 #
# They all want me #
# 大家都把我来爱 #
# I'm a monster, I'm a... #
# 我是怪物 我是怪... #
I didn't do that.
我什么都没干